Kevin C Jones

Manchester, England, United Kingdom



him@kevincjones.co.uk



% 07557682932



linkedin.com/in/kevin-c-jones-7a22372

Summary

A software engineer for over 15 years of professional experience, including 6 years as a technical lead, well versed in agile methodologies.

Comfortable in large and small agile squads, handling diverse application needs. Specialised in forging teams who value well written extendable code, fast release cycles and short feedback loops.

Sharing knowledge and encouraging others to do so is paramount to helping teams grow and succeed.

Currently specialised in Javascript/Typescript using Angular to build single page applications for the web, mobile and desktop. Have previously done full stack using NodeJS and a mix of MongoDB and SQL, currently expanding my experiences using .NET Core and microservice architectures.

Experience



Frontend Tech Lead

Push Doctor

Feb 2018 - Present (2 years 8 months +)

Pushdoctor facilitates online doctor consultations, and are currently leading the charge with the NHS and integrating with GP surgeries around the country.

Some headlines so far:

- Lead a team of 6 Frontend engineers across two geolocations using Angular and AngularJS
- Setup the continuous deployment pipelines in Azure DevOps with unit tests, e2e tests, static code scanning and pull requesting analysis using Sonarcloud, deploying to multiple targets including S3 buckets with Cloudfront.
- Moved the multiple Angular (version 8 to date) applications into a mono-repository architecture (Nx), with an emphasis on developing a reusable CDK across multiple application using Angular Material.
- Introduced unit test coverage and hit 80% coverage for our core products within 12 months.
- Developed and integrated a feature testing system to enable the product team to explore new concepts, measure results and fail faster.
- Created a team knowledge-base in Confluence which included a golden path onboarding new staff, playbooks for maintaining all parts of the system (removing any bus factors of 1) and an RFC section where any developer could articulate new ideas and concepts.
- Ran a weekly chapter meeting for the team to discuss anything, show and tell recent work, and share learnings or industry changes.
- Ran regular 1-2-1's with my team and other departments to encourage a cohesive and collaborative atmosphere.
- Worked closely with Product and Business Analysts to help identify the best way to marry the business needs with technical direction.

Lead Frontend Developer

Nucleus Global

Jan 2014 - Feb 2018 (4 years 2 months)

Leading a team of front end developers creating medical communicational materials on mobile and desktop. There are no limits to the technology we'll experiment with to stay ahead of the competition but its important to us to always choose the right tool for the job at hand.

Still heavily involved technically in the development side with projects in production using Angular2, React +Redux and NodeJS middleware tiers, and manage the developer operations of the front end team, keeping our continuous deployment servers running.

As a coherent communicator, i'm often explaining technical team descisions with stakeholders and presenting to large audiences.

I add the most value to a project when involved early on with clients to help them architect the solutions they 'need' and helping them understand the boundaries and opportunities they have before them. A certain amount of business analysis is fairly standard in order to get to the root of 'why' a client wants something.

Senior Applications Developer

Nucleus Global

Aug 2010 - Jan 2014 (3 years 6 months)

I deliver any and all interactive materials for any and all who require them. A great industry which relies heavily on standing out in a fiercely competitive arena of medical communications. I foresee a huge potential to tap the large history of innovative, eye catching and publicity driving digital solutions I'm accustomed to delivering.

Technical Director

Twisted Studio Ltd

Aug 2006 - Jul 2010 (4 years)

Co-founded and managed as an award winning graduate start-up business we took our expertise in digital software, game development and design and carved out a cutting edge studio which specialised in engaging digital experiences.

I left Twisted to move back to Manchester and seek out new professional challenges.

Intern Games Programmer

Onisoft UK

Jun 2004 - Aug 2005 (1 year 3 months)

Developing titles from start to finish on handheld devices like Pocket PC and Palm and having one artist at disposal. Other duties entailed Max scripting some A.I programming and Flash development.

Freelance Developer

Freelancer

Sep 2002 - May 2005 (2 years 9 months)

During my University years I was able to offer my services to a number of small businesses and independents who were in need of software developments and prototypes. As educational as it was profitable, it was this with my work experience years to follow later that cemented the realisation that I was going to run a business from now on.

Education



Teesside University

Bsc (Hons), Computer Games Programming 2001 - 2006 Attained a First Class Honours Degree Result

Skills

Software Development • TypeScript • Team Leadership • Business Development • Project Management • Agile Methodologies • Test Driven Development • Solution Architecture • Software Project Management • JavaScript